When working with documents, there may
be occasions where you need to protect
the document which will restrict access
or editing rights to the document.
As you can see, I have a demonstration
document on the screen in front of
me, and I'm going to demonstrate how
you can apply a password to access
the file, and also a password to
restrict any editing of the document.
The first thing I need to do is
I need to navigate up to the top
toolbar and select the tools option.
And then, from the drop down,
the protect document option.
This brings up the password
protect dialog box.
So in the very first one, which is
set a password to open this document
and we'll just type in password,
press enter and it will ask me to
enter that again and select okay.
If I click okay, now that has set the
password, but that won't be active
till I've actually saved the document.
So if I just go to File and I'll
close the document and it will
ask me if I want to save it.
Select yes.
So now the forms letter when I open
that, it will ask for a password.
Select okay.
And that will then open the document.
Another option is, is to restrict
the editing of the document.
As you can see at the moment I can put my
cursor in the document and make changes.
So I'll just undo those changes.
So what I need to do is I
need to restrict the editing.
So if I click on the tools button again,
and go down to protect document and I'll
just take off the password, I will then
enter a password to modify the document.
So anybody who wishes to modify
it must have the password.
Click okay.
Enter the password again, select OK.
And again, this won't be active
until I save the documents so
I'm going to go to File, Close
and then make sure I select save.
So now when I click on it, it
will ask me for a password.
So if I want to modify that,
I must put the password in.
I can open the document, but I
would have to click read only
if I didn't have the password.
And then I would not be able to make
any changes no matter what I pressed.
They could make a duplicate copy of
the document and make changes but the
original copy would not be changed.
There's no way anybody could change
that without having the actual password.